Harvey Pitkin Papers 1884-1968 Mss.Ms.Coll.78
American Philosophical Society
Harvey Pitkin Papers
1884-1968
Mss.Ms.Coll.78
American Philosophical Society
15.5 Linear feet
The linguist Harvey Pitkin has worked on several of the indigenous languages of Northern California, with a particular interest in Wintu, Patwin, and Yuki. A student of A. L. Kroeber, Pitkin was a member of the Department of Linguistics at the University of California, Berkeley, and later at Columbia University before his retirement in the late 1980s. The Pitkin Papers contain materials recorded or accumuluted by Harvey Pitkin during the course of his study of American Indian languages, including not only his own fieldnotes and research on Wintu and Yuki, but originals and copies of notes, notebooks, and slipfiles by A. L. Kroeber, A. M. Halpern, John P. Harrington, John Alden Mason, Paul Radin, Hans Uldall, Donald Ultan, T. T. Waterman, and others. These include important information on Atsugewi, Kwakiutl, Luiseno, Pomo, Wappo, Yahi, and Yana, and include some data on the consultants Ralph Moore (Yuki) and Ishi (Yahi).
Pitkin, Harvey
Related Archival Materials note
The Bancroft Library at the University of California, Berkeley, houses an extensive collection of the papers of A. L. Kroeber.
Separated Materials note
Transferred to printed materials:
Ralph Beals, Address in memory of Alfred L. Kroeber, delivered at the Annual Meeting of the Southwestern Anthropological Association, March 31, 1961, at the University of California, Santa Barbara.
The originals of Kroeber's Yuki notebooks were transferred to the Kroeber Papers, Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley in 1999. Photocopies of all were retained.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Pitkin Papers were donated by Harvey Pitkin in February 1993 (acc. no. 1993-227ms).
Arrangement note
The collection is divided into three series:
Series I. Patwin and Wintu Materials 1884-1957 13 boxes; 7 linear feet
Series II. Yuki Materials 1900-1968 12 boxes; 7.25 linear feet
Series III. Miscellaneous Materials 1904-1958 3 boxes; 1.25 linear feet
Scope and Contents note
The Pitkin Papers (1884-1968) are comprised of 15.5 linear feet of materials relating to Harvey Pitkin's research on the indigenous languages of northern California. The collection consists primarily of research ntoes and notebooks, vocabularies, and slip files, with some texts and other manuscripts, correspondence, and phonetic tracings. An inveterate collector of materials relating to the languages he studied, Pitkin accumulated originals and copies of the works of other specialists in California languages, including his mentor, A. L. Kroeber, A. M. Halpern, John P. Harrington, John Alden Mason, Paul Radin, Hans Uldall, Donald Ultan, T. T. Waterman, and others. These include important information on Atsugewi, Kwakiutl, Luiseno, Pomo, Wappo, Yahi, and Yana, and include some data on the consultants Ralph Moore (Yuki) and Ishi (Yahi).
Native American Images Note: Notebooks with pencil sketches of Patwin dance formations and artifacts, color pencil palatograms of Yuki words, and kymograms of Yuki, Yahi, and Patwin disyllables, polysyllables, and sonorants. Phonetic tracings graphed by Pitkin, other contributors include A.M. Halpern and A.L. Kroeber. Of note, Yuki material recorded by Ralph Moore and Yahi tracings from Ishi. Northern Californian indigenous languages collected from 1910-1958. Also includes 31 black and white photographs of Pitkin's Wintu consultants, 1956-1957.
Biographical/Historical note
Born in New York City on April 22, 1928, Harvey Pitkin received his doctorate in linguistics from the University of California, Berkeley, in 1963. Under the direction of Alfred L. Kroeber, he directed his attention to a study of the dialects of Wintu (Wintu and Patwin), a Penutian language of Northern California, and later to Yuki and Wappo, California languages of uncertain affinity. Relatively early in Pitkin's career, Kroeber entrusted him with his invaluable collection of Yuki notes and notebooks, feeling that Piktin's ear was better attuned to the subtleties of the language.
In 1960, Pitkin was hired as Assistant Professor in the Department of Linguistics at Berkeley, earning promotion to Associate in 1964 and full professor in 1980. He later served on the faculty at Columbia University until his retirement.
Pitkin's publications included two major monographs, Wintu Grammar, University of California Publications in Linguistics 94 (1985), and Wintu Dictionary University of California Publications in Linguistics 95, the former bassed largely on his dissertation. Among several articles he wrote were "A Comparative Survey of California Penutian," "A Bibliography of the Wintun Family of Languages," "A Comparison of Miwok and Wintun" (with Sylvia A. Broadbent), "Language and Culture," "Some Problems of Method in Anthropological Linguistics," "Coyote and Bullhead, a Wintu Text," "Squirrel and Acorn-Woman (Wintu)," and "Two Plus Two Makes Two: An Analysis of Wintu Numerals."
Boas, Franz, 1858-1942; Haas, Mary R., (Mary Rosamond), 1910-1996; Harrington, John Peabody; Hymes, Dell H.; Ishi, d. 1916; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960; Li, Fanggui; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967; Radin, Paul, 1883-1959; Uldall, Hans Jørgen, 1907-1957; Ultan, Donald; Waterman, T. T., (Thomas Talbot), 1885-; Atsugewi language; California Indians; Cherokee language; Field notes.; Graphs.; Indians of North America--California; Indians of North America--Languages; Kwakiutl language; Kymograms; Language and languages--Phonetic transcriptions; Luiseno language; Maidu language; Sketches.; Slip files; Wappo dialect; Wintu language; Yahi language; Yana language; Yuki language
- Series I. Patwin and Wintu Materials, 1884-1957; 7.0 linear feet (Box Series I: 1-2)
  Scope and Contents note
  Notes and notebooks, vocabularies, slip files, texts, manuscripts, and phonetic tracings relating to Wintu, Patwin (Southern Wintu), and Nomlaki (Central Wintu) languages. The materials are arranged by format, and then filed alphabetically by the name of the collector or recorder
  - Series I-A. Research notes, 1900-1957; 28 folders (Box Series IA: 1-2)
    Loose notes and notebooks on Wintu and Patwin linguistics and ethnography, arranged alphabetically by author or collector and, within that, by title. Although most of the material if original, the series include Jeremiah Curtin's "Wintu words and names" and photocopies of Roland Dixon's Wintu notebooks.
    The series also contains materials collected by other linguists and ethnographers, including nine notebooks kept by A. M. Halpern, 1936 (see related notebooks in Servies III-A). Halpern's notebooks include notes from several locations, including Colusa, Enterprise, Rumsey, and Stonyford. The series also includes an important series of notebooks by A. L. Kroeber, 1900-1924, concerning various dialects or areas of Hill, River, Colusa, and Long Valley Patwin. These notebooks also contain occasional information on Atsugewi, Yana, Salt Pomo, Lake Miwok, Kato, and Pomo.
    Finally, the series includes an index to Paul Radin's work on Patwin and Wintun, notebooks by Radin, T. T. Waterman (on southeastern Wintu and Patwin phonetics), Howard Wilson (on Grimes Patwin, taken 1903 an annotated by Kroeber), and a computer printout of Donald Ultan's fieldnotes on Patwin (arranged by book number, see also Series I-B).
    - Wintu words and names, Photocopy; Curtin, Jeremiah (Box Series IA-1)
      Original at Smithsonian Institution
    - Wintu notebooks, n.d.; Photocopy, 3 folders; Dixon, Roland Burrage, 1875-1934 (Box Series IA-1)
      Originals at Peabody Museum and Library, Harvard University.
    - Wintu notebooks, n.d.; 9 notebooks; Halpern, A. M. (Box Series IA-1)
      - Butte City, Patwin notebook, 1936; Halpern, A. M. (Box Series IA-1)
      - Colusa I, Patwin notebook, 1936; Halpern, A. M. (Box Series IA-1)
      - Colusa II, Patwin notebook, 1936; Halpern, A. M. (Box Series IA-1)
        Native American images note: pencil sketch by informant William Benjamin, dance diagram.
      - Enterprise I, Wintu notebook, 1936; Halpern, A. M. (Box Series IA-1)
      - Enterprise II, Reddings, Wintu notebook, 1936; Halpern, A. M. (Box Series IA-1)
      - Grindstone Rs., Patwin notebook, 1936; Halpern, A. M. (Box Series IA-1)
      - Rumsey I, Patwin notebook, 1936; Halpern, A. M. (Box Series IA-1)
      - Rumsey II, Patwin notebook, 1936; Halpern, A. M. (Box Series IA-1)
        Native American images note: pencil sketches by informant Daisy Lowell Lorenzo of baskets, bowls, arrow designs.
      - Stonyford, Nomlaki notebook, 1936; Halpern, A. M. (Box Series IA-1)
    - Index to Radin materials on Patwin and Wintun (Box Series IA-1)
    - Atsugewi, Yana, Wintun, Hat Creek notebook, 1900; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IA-1)
      Pp. 39-50 cut out, perhaps for Roland Dixon.
    - List of Patwin linguistic data in keeping of A. L. Kroeber, transferred to [U.C. Berkeley] Linguistics Dept., 1957; Photocopy, 3 folders; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IA-1)
    - List of Patwin words [to be kymographed?], 1957, n.d.; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960; Waterman, T. T., (Thomas Talbot), 1885- (Box Series IA-1)
    - Notebooks, 1901-1924; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IA-1)
      - Notebook 22: Huchnom-Yuki, Wintun, Wappo, 1901, 1903, 1908; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IA-1)
        KFI: Dr. 3, item 3
      - Notebook 201: Hill Patwin, River Patwin, 1923; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IA-1)
        Native American images note: pencil sketches by informant Peter Wilson of diagrams with settlements noted.
      - Notebook 202: Hill Patwin, Central Wintun, Salt Pomo, 1923; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IA-1)
        Native American images note: pencil sketches of diagrams, creation figure.
      - Notebook 204: N.E. Pomo, Central Wintun, 1923; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IA-1)
      - Notebook 206: Lake Miwok, Long V[ally] Patwin, Kato, Pomo (Lower Lake), 1923; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IA-1)
      - Notebook 209: River Patwin, 1924; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IA-1)
      - Notebook 210: River Patwin, 1924; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IA-1)
    - Phonetic notes on Colusa Patwin, 1910; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IA-1)
      Native American images note: pencil sketches by informant Tom Odock of phonetic symbols with words.
    - S. Wintun, Patwin notebook, 1916; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IA-1)
    - Wintun, Patwin notebook, 1931; Radin, Paul, 1883-1959 (Box Series IA-2)
    - Patwin fieldnotes, n.d.; Ultan, Donald (Oversize IA, Folder 1-7)
      - Book 1 "H U", n.d.; Ultan, Donald (Oversize 1, Folder Series IA-1)
      - Book 2 "H U", n.d.; Ultan, Donald (Oversize 1, Folder Series IA-2)
      - Book 3 "H U", n.d.; Ultan, Donald (Oversize 1, Folder Series IA-3)
      - Book 4 "A U", n.d.; Ultan, Donald (Oversize 1, Folder Series IA-4)
      - Book 5 "H U", n.d.; Ultan, Donald (Oversize 1, Folder Series IA-5)
      - Book 6 "L U, C U, R U, T U", n.d.; Ultan, Donald (Oversize 1, Folder Series IA-6)
      - Book 7 (River Patwin?) "R U", n.d.; Ultan, Donald (Oversize 1, Folder Series IA-7)
    - Notes on Patwin phonetics, 1957, n.d.; Waterman, T. T., (Thomas Talbot), 1885- (Box Series IA-2)
    - S.E. Wintun notebook, 1910; Waterman, T. T., (Thomas Talbot), 1885- (Box Series IA-2)
    - Linguistic notes on Grimes Patwin, 1903, 1957; Wilson, Howard B. (Box Series IA-2)
  - Series I-B. Vocabularies and slip files, 1884-1932; 4 folders, 11 boxes (Box Series IB-2)
    Pitkin's Wintu grammar slip file, arranged alphabetically by English word or phrase.
    The series also includes photocopies of vocabularies by Jeremiah Curtin (1884) and Paul Radin, from his Patwin-English dictionarym, a Suisun vocabulary taken by John Alden Mason, a Patwin vocabulary recorded by Kroeber, and computer printouts of Ultan's Patwin to English vocabulary arranged in alphabetical order by phonetic spelling (see his fieldnotes in Series I-A).
    - Wintun vocabulary, n.d.; Photocopy; Curtin, Jeremiah (Box Series IB-2)
      Originals at Smithsonian Institution
    - Colusa Patwin, River Patwin vocabulary, 1909; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IB-2)
    - Suisun vocabulary, 1916; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967 (Box Series IB-2)
    - Patwin-English dictionary, 1932?; Photocopy; Radin, Paul, 1883-1959 (Box Series IB-2)
      Original at APS.
    - Patwin [Dictionary], Computer printout; Ultan, Donald (Oversize 1 / Series IB)
      - Folder 1: "A U", n.d.; Ultan, Donald (Oversize 1, Folder Series IB-1)
      - Folder 2: "C U", n.d.; Ultan, Donald (Oversize 1, Folder Series IB-2)
      - Folder 3: "H U", n.d.; Ultan, Donald (Oversize 1, Folder Series IB-3)
      - Folder 4: "L U", n.d.; Ultan, Donald (Oversize 1, Folder Series IB-4)
      - Folder 5: "R U", n.d.; Ultan, Donald (Oversize 1, Folder Series IB-5)
      - Folder 6: "T U", n.d.; Ultan, Donald (Oversize 1, Folder Series IB-6)
    - Patwin slipfile, n.d.; ca.1,800 slips; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IB - Kroeber Slipfile 1)
    - Wintu Grammar: English-Wintu slipfile, n.d.; ca.27,000 slips, 10 boxes; Pitkin, Harvey (Box Series IB - Pitkin Slipfile 1-10)
      - Box 1: A-Be, n.d.; Pitkin, Harvey (Box Series IB - Pitkin Slipfile 1)
      - Box 2: Bi-Cri, n.d.; Pitkin, Harvey (Box Series IB - Pitkin Slipfile 2)
      - Box 3: Cro-Fa, n.d.; Pitkin, Harvey (Box Series IB - Pitkin Slipfile 3)
      - Box 4: Fe-G, n.d.; Pitkin, Harvey (Box Series IB - Pitkin Slipfile 4)
      - Box 5: H-Li, n.d.; Pitkin, Harvey (Box Series IB - Pitkin Slipfile 5)
      - Box 6: Lo-Op, n.d.; Pitkin, Harvey (Box Series IB - Pitkin Slipfile 6)
      - Box 7: Or-Rh, n.d.; Pitkin, Harvey (Box Series IB - Pitkin Slipfile 7)
      - Box 8: Ri-Sop, n.d.; Pitkin, Harvey (Box Series IB - Pitkin Slipfile 8)
      - Box 9: Sor-Tho, n.d.; Pitkin, Harvey (Box Series IB - Pitkin Slipfile 9)
      - Box 10: Thr-Z, n.d.; Pitkin, Harvey (Box Series IB - Pitkin Slipfile 10)
  - Series I-C. Texts and manuscripts, 1909-1957; 9 folders (Box Series IC-2)
    manuscripts and texts relating to Patwin and Wintu languages, grammar, speech, and songs. The series includes an annotated photocopy of Jaime de Angulo's "Patwin Language," S. A. Barrett's transcriptions and translations of speech and song recordings, Kroeber's notes on linguistics, Radibn's "Grammatical Sketch" (outlining prefixation, suffixation, and syntax), and T. T. Waterman's notes on Patwin phonetics.
    - Patwin language, 1929; Photocopy, 2 folders; Angulo, Jaime de (Box Series IC-2)
    - Speech and song recordings -- Transcriptions and translations, 1909, 1957; Barrett, S. A. (Box Series IC-2)
    - Notes on texts transcribed Oct. 24-25, 1909, 1957; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IC-2)
    - Patwin texts and notes, and preliminary linguistic analysis, 1909; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IC-2)
    - Grammatical sketch prefixation, n.d.; Radin, Paul, 1883-1959 (Box Series IC-2)
    - Grammatical sketch suffixation, n.d.; Radin, Paul, 1883-1959 (Box Series IC-2)
    - Grammatical sketch syntax (part II), n.d.; Radin, Paul, 1883-1959 (Box Series IC-2)
    - Phonetics of the Patwin language [oe, the phonetic system of the Southeastern Wintun dialect], Waterman, T. T., (Thomas Talbot), 1885- (Box Series IC-2)
  - Series I-D. Phonetic tracings, n.d.; 1 folder (Box Series ID-2)
    Phonetic tracings, specifically kymograms (in original form or as photoprints) of Patwin words.
    - Patwin phonetic tracings -- kymograms, n.d.; Photoprints (Box Series ID-2)
      Marked Fig. 1-3, 5, 7. Image note: 5 graphs.
- Series II. Yuki Materials, 1900-1968; 7.25 linear feet (Box Series II: 3-8)
  Material gathered by A. L. Kroeber, who sent a list of his files to Dell Hymes (see Ser. II-A).
  - Series II-A. Research notes, 1900-1960; 48 folders (Box Series IIA: 3-4)
    Notes arranged alphabetically by author or recorder, and then alphabetically by title. One folder includes comments by Kroeber and Hymes on Hans Uldall's "Preliminary report on Yuki tones," and there is a related file on Yuki tones.
    The series is rich in material collected by A. L. Kroeber, including a series of notebooks filed by number (e.g. Notebook 22) or title, when unnumbered, a few folders containing homonyms and near-homonyms or minimal and near-minial pairs (one done by Pitkin), as well as several folders of notes and a list of Yuki material prepared for Dell Hymes, glossed with reference to the Kroeber drawer and item numbers, as originally stored. The notes range from 1900 to 1932, with annotations made in 1957-1958. The notebooks dating from 1900-1908 are largely concerned with Yuki language and stories, and some contain material on Wintu, Pomo, Sinkyone, and Coast Yurok. Among other items are a folder containing Fang-Kuei (Fanggui) Li's notes on Yuki tones from 1927, with annotations from 1957; two folders of Pitkin's notes on materials received from Kroeber and on Yuki phonemics, 1957, several folders of Hans Uldall's notes on Yuki stems, tones, and suffixes, and a bibliography by Kroeber of Mayo-Polynesian languages.
    - [Comments on Hans Uldall's "Preliminary report on Yuki tones" with annotations by Kroeber], [1958?]; Kroeber, A. L. and Dell Hymes (Box Series IIA-3)
    - Data on tones and tones traced, 1927; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-3)
      KFI: Dr. 1, item 22
    - Grammatical notes, 1927; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-3)
      Noptes on kymograph.
      - Folder 1, 1957, n.d.; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-3)
        KFI: Dr. 1, item 6a
      - Folder 2, 1902, 1957; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-3)
        KFI: Dr. 1, item 6b
    - Homonyms?, n.d.; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-3)
      KFI: Dr. 1, item 22 (3a)
    - Indexes to notebooks and loose-leaf notes, 1910, 1957; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-3)
      KFI: Dr. 1, item 3a, 3b
    - List of Kroeber files in University of California, Berkeley's Dept. of Anthropology archvies (for Dell Hymes), 1957; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-3)
    - List of minimal and near-minimal pair, or, homonyms and near-homonyms, 1932, 1957; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-3)
      KFI: Dr. 1, item 20c
    - N 1-41: Newly determined or redetermined grammatical elements (suffixes), 1932, 1957; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-3)
      KFI: Dr. 1, item 8
    - N 42-95: Verb stems in rough alphabetical order, ha-nA, 1932, 1957-1958; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-3)
      KFI: Dr. 1, item 9
    - N 96-162: Verb stems, adverbs, pronouns, adjectives, particles, 1932, 1957; Kroeber, A. L. and Hans Uldall (Box Series IIA-3)
      KFI: Dr. 1, item 11
    - Notebooks: Yuki, 1900-1908; Photocopy; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-3)
      Originals transferred to the Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley, 1999.
      - Notebook 19: Yuki, 1900; Photocopy; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-3)
        KFI: Dr. 1, item 4
      - Notebook 20: Yuki, 1901; Photocopy; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-3)
      - Notebook 21: Yuki, 1901; Photocopy; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-3)
      - Notebook 22: Huchnom-Yuki, Wintun, Wappo, 1901, 1903, 1908; Photocopy; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-3)
      - Notebook 23: Yuki, 1901; Photocopy; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-3)
        KFI: Dr. 1, item 4, "Culture and language."
      - Notebook 27: Yuki, 1902; Photocopy; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-3)
        KFI: Dr. 3, item 3, "Wildcat and coyote."
      - Notebook 28: Yuki, 1902; Photocopy; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-3)
        KFI: Dr. 1, item 4, "Coyote myth in English."
      - Notebook 29: Yuki, 1902; Photocopy; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-3)
        KFI: Dr. 3, item 3, "Taikomol and begi. Of coyote."
      - Notebook 30: Yuki, 1902; Photocopy; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-4)
      - Notebook 31: Yuki, 1902; Photocopy; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-4)
        KFI: Dr. 1, item 4, "Coyote text."
      - Notebook 32: Yuki, 1900; Photocopy; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-4)
        KFI: Dr. 3, item 3, "Coyote and crow," "Ham nam wok" [first mentruation dance].
      - Notebook 46: Yuki, 1902; Photocopy; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-4)
      - Notebook 47: Yuki, 1902; Photocopy; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-4)
    - Notes on powers (burial of the dead, scalping, beheading, tattooing), n.d.; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-4)
      KFI: Dr. 1, item 7
    - Notes on Round Valley informants, Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-4)
    - Notes on Yuki linguistic material transfrred to Linguistics Dept. for Harvey Pitkin, 1903, 1957; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-4)
    - Stem list: nouns, adjectives, verbs, suffixes, 1958, n.d.; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-4)
      KFI: Dr. 1, item 15
    - Terminal consonant combinations in Uldall's monosyllabic stem list, U 10-16, n.d.; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-4)
    - Tone texts and comparisons of Yuki words with Spanish and English, Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-4)
      KFI: Dr. 1, item 17, Wildcat, Coyote and crow texts
    - Verb forms and suffixes: V 1-25, 1931; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-4)
      KFI: Dr. 1, item 18
    - Vebr stems: hA-nA; and, Noun and verb stems: P, P', and S, 1931-913, 1957, 1960; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-4)
    - Yuki notes, 1906; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-4)
    - Yuki, Huchnom, Kabenapo, Pomo notebook, 1917; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-4)
    - Yuki phonemes, verb stem list, suffixes, 1957; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-4)
      See related material in: Ser. II-A. Piktin, Havrey, Yuki phonemics.
    - Yuki tones -- notes, n.d.; Photocopy; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-4)
    - Yuki tones and stem syllable types: T 1-38, 1932, 1957; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-4)
    - Yuki suffixes -- notes, 1932, 1958; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box Series IIA-4)
      KFI: Dr. 1, item 20.
      Noun and verb suffixes, and suffix tones, and their meanings (includes 2p. index).
    - Yuki tones -- notes, 1927, 1957, n.d.; Li, Fanggui (Box Series IIA-4)
      KFI: Dr. 1, item 5e.
      See Ser. II-D for words traced on the kymograph.
    - Notes on Yuki and Patwin material received from A. L. Kroeber and Mary Haas, 1957; Pitkin, Harvey (Box Series IIA-4)
    - Yuki phonemes, verb stem list, suffixes, 1957; Pitkin, Harvey (Box Series IIA-4)
      KFI: Dr. 1, item 22.
      Contains comparisons of equivalent orthographies of Kroeber, Uldall, proposed [Pitkin], and phonetic
    - Monosyllabic noun stems: TU 39-44, 1931-1932, 1958?; Uldall, Hans (Box Series IIA-4)
      KFI: Dr. 1, item 10.